Siobhán Baines

Leeds, West Yorkshire
Telephone: 07766740070
Email: baines.smb@gmail.com
LinkedIn: Siobhan Baines

Profile

Junior Full Stack Developer with some proficiency in both Front-End and Back-End development utilising HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and a particular interest in Python. Currently undertaking a Professional Diploma in Software Development to bring skillset into the 21st century. Equipped with 30 years' experience in delivering a variety of solutions on the IBM AS400 platform and compatible API's. Troubleshooting and problem-solving skills are second nature as well as knowledge transfer, change management and requirements gathering. Experienced in ERP development and support, working with Relational Data, Application Programming, Interfaces and using a variety of programming languages and technologies. Analytical and methodical, staying current on the latest thinking and techniques and continually looking for improvement.

Education

Full Stack Developer: Professional Diploma in Software Development - credit rated by Edinburgh Napier University

Qualification Date: Estimated July 2021

MS4 - Full Stack Frameworks using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,

Python and Django

MS3 - Data Centric Development using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,

Python, Flask and MongoDB

MS2 - Interactive Front-End Development using HTML5, CSS3 and

JavaScript

MS1 - User Centric Front-End Development using HTML5 and CSS3

Ciara & Sam's Wedding

Our Family Favourites

Harry Potter Memory Game

Siobhan Baines Portfolio

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, GitHub, Python, JavaScript, jQuery, MySql, RPGIII, RPGIV, RPG400, RPGLE, CL, CLLE, AS400 SQL

Cloud Technologies: Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS, Flask, Django Frameworks, GitHub/Gitpod, MongoDB, Heroku, Google APIs, Font

ERP systems: JDE World 7.3 & 9.4 (including AR, AP, GL, SOX, PO, SO), Data3

Applications: Create! Print, Bartender, Aldon, BizAgi, BRMS, MQ, IIB, Transform, Robot Scheduler, Showcase Query, Microsoft

Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)

Transferable Expertise

Software Development: Produce operationally valid solutions utilising analysis, problem definition, requirements gathering, solution development and proposed solutions. Confer with testers and studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes. **Leadership:** Self-reliant, strong critical decision making, motivating, team building, delegating and monitoring quality **Stakeholder Management:** Forming, monitoring and maintaining constructive relationships by collaborating with stakeholders' expectations at all organisation levels, understanding their needs and delivering against agreed timescales

Analysis: Ability to identify and implement systemic to support effective transformative change. Implement set of practices and processes that lead to development of a set of well-formed business requirements from which the business solutions can be developed

Requirements Gathering: Expertise in utilising a variety of investigative techniques to gather information from stakeholders and develop ways to manage their interests and expectations

Continuous Improvement: Proven ability to identify areas for further development, and able to support others in the process. Has an analytical and problem-solving approach to work. Excels at prioritising flexibly to meet rapidly changing needs. Adept at crisis and risk management

Key Skills

- Critical thinking
- Collaboration
- Developer in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, SQL, RPG, CL
- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- Process Improvement
- Risk analysis

- Applications Support
- Knowledge Transfer
- Attention to Detail
- Achieving strict deadlines
- Adaptable to change
- Accurate with attention to detail

Employment History

Dec 2020 to date

Freelance Business Analyst - Baines SM Ltd

Studying Diploma in Software Development with Code Institute

Mar 2020 – Dec 2020

Freelance Business Analyst - Baines SM Ltd/ Premier Farnell

- Collaborate with a variety of 3rd Party and internal, local and international stakeholders to enable successful implementation of new outsourced financial systems and produce FRS documentation.
- Demonstrated strong communication skills to liaise with stakeholders at all levels, including IT, Finance, suppliers,
 Project Managers, Finance Directors, Business Owners and IT technicians
- Managed the delivery of numerous small projects, such as the redesign of the company's ecommerce emails and detailing requirements for a new invoice feed to a European government department

Oct 2019 – Jan 2020 Technology Lead – Infosys @ Hallmark Cards

- Provided Application Support, identified requirements of projects as well as business and technical knowledge transfer
- Liaised with clients for project briefing, consultation, installation and closeout reviews
- Supervised activities between internal and external resources, and facilitated smooth workflow for service delivery

2016 – 2019 **Business Analyst/Senior JDE Support Technician** - Hallmark Cards

- Collaborated with a variety of internal stakeholders to provide on-site support for the Japan office systems upgrade
- Served as Consultant across financial reporting, acted as liaison for Australian and Central Europe system upgrades
- Delivered complex knowledge transfer sessions to Infosys across multiple process areas, to facilitate take-on of services
- IBM MQ and IIB administrator; co-ordination and management of software upgrade with external suppliers
- Supported the delivery of a new Pay-On-Scan process, modified a self-bill process to meet changing business requirements for major customers. Held responsibility for the role-based security module and purchase order approvals process
- Simultaneously supported JDE World legacy 7.3 and current 9.4 systems, IBM MQ and IIB, and Robot Scheduler
- End-to-end management for the development deployment through Aldon LMi

2012 - 2018

IT Finance Stream Lead/JDE World Systems & Application Support Analyst - Hallmark Cards

- Pivotal member in the Hallmark strategic business transformation project which de-risked the core legacy system JDE World 7.3 upgraded to vanilla JDE World 9.3.1
- Gained insights into the needs of the business by undertaking requirements gathering, As-Is and To-Be process flows, business specifications, technical specifications, system testing, support testers throughout UAT, go-live data transfers and post go-live support
- Played a key role in the configuration of a self-bill invoicing and reconciliation model, utilised expertise to provide technical guidance across the financial module, assisted in configuring the new to 9.3 role-based security module, supporting legacy JDE 7.3 systems and managing multiple IBM AS400 systems operation tasks including the BRMS backup system

2006 - 2011

Analyst Programmer - Hallmark Cards

- Enhanced efficiency by liaising with the business, to gain an understanding of their needs; utilised influencing skills within meetings to set acceptable archiving criteria to reduce the amount of legacy data in JDE.
- Expanded the Ship Confirmation suite of programs to interface with SAP EWM; supported users by producing a technical user guide and created various labels in an antiquated Bar-Tender system
- Liaised with stakeholders, developed and implemented a data archiving suite including a mechanism for data retrieval
- Developed and embedded interfaces to the Savoye LM7 warehousing system including the business-critical Ship Confirmation suite of programs
- Led projects including a project to increase the expiry year within JDE to ensure bespoke changes were compatible

Key Achievements:

- Successfully represented colleagues through TUPE and redundancy processes
- On-site Japanese go-live hyper-care support, JDE security and PO approval design
- First point of contact IBM MQ, IIB, Robot, Aldon, Showcase and role-based security

Jan 2005 - Dec 2006 1st/2nd Line Support and Development Analysis Programmer - Jacuzzi UK

Jul 2002 - Jan 2005 Analyst Programmer - William Hill Organization

May 1990 - Jul 2002 Company Secretary and Contract Analyst Programmer - Hapwell Ltd

Oct 1989 – Apr 1990 Analyst Programmer – Higham's Computer Services Ltd

Sept 1987 – Oct 1989 Analyst Programmer – Baxter Healthcare

Education and Training History

BSc (Hons) Open (Strategy, Collaboration and Finance)
Professional Certificate in Accounting
Diploma of Higher Education Open
RPG 4 crossover & ILE
ITIL Foundation Certified

Certificate in Business Studies
AAT Level 2 Certificate for Accounting Technicians
Broker Administration
TOPS training course
2 A' levels and 8 O' levels Inc Mathematics and English